Paul R. Reesman

www.linkedin.com/in/paulreesman

Reesmanp.github.io

(480)580-8588

Paul.R.Reesman@gmail.com

Objective

An experienced full stack software engineer who has experience in IHE healthcare and enterprise systems. I have professional experience with the full stack and the entire development cycle. My daily duties require me to to be proficient in: JavaScript (React and NodeJS), Cache ObjectScript, BASH, Python, PHP, Java, HTML5, and CSS. Having built several RESTful API's, I prefer the HapiJS framework however I have built API's in Vert.x3, Cache ObjectScript, and Django.

Professional Experience

Nordstrom 9/2017 - Present

Engineer I Seattle, WA

- Full Stack Developer using ReactJS, NodeJS, and C#
- Develop features for the product page of the Nordstrom website.
- Fix bugs found by users and other member of the team and deploy the changes.
- Maintain a stable environment and provide support during holiday and anniversary sales.

Seattle Children's Hospital

1/2016 - 9/2017

Application Developer

Seattle, WA

- Full Stack Developer using ReactJS, NodeJS, C#, Cache Objectscript, Bash, PHP, and Python.
- Architected and implemented 3 RESTful API's using ObjectScript and NodeJS (HapiJS).
- Lead developer on two separate Proof of Concepts which caused an increase in core application performance.
- Used ReactJS to create a dynamic front end interface for our applications.
- Managed our Atlassian suite of apps including Jira, Bitbucket, Bamboo, Confluence, and Fisheye.
- Tracked and resolved bugs, enhancements, and tasks through Jira.
- Wrote PHP to integrate our systems with Okta to allow a Single Sign On (SSO) service.

Coding With Kids

3/2016 - 2/2017

Instructor Redmond, WA

- Taught children from early elementary school through high school the art and science behind computer science.
- Taught children how to code with Scratch, Python, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS.

United States Army

7/2008 - 12/2012

Forward Observer / Team Leader

Fort Lewis, WA

- Assigned to 75th Ranger Regiment and granted secret clearance due to sensitive duties required of a Ranger Forward Observer.
- Maintained positive control and accountability of over \$350,000 worth of equipment.
- Awarded the Joint Service Commendation Medal for controlling multiple aircraft which allowed for the success of countless special operations missions.
- Took charge of 25 to 30 personnel during exhaustive details which was instrumental for the logistics of ongoing special operations missions.

Github Projects

Node-HISP

- Implement a fully functional secure mail server that functions as a HISP which forces mutual TLS.
- Front end built with ReactJS and backend built with NodeJS using HapiJS.

Scandinavian Festival Booth Tool

- Implementing a tool to perform front and back end restaurant transactions over an ad-hoc network.
- Designing the program to predict future customer transactions by using supervised machine learning linear regression techniques.
- Writing a friendly interface using ReactJS wrapped in Electron to be able to be delivered as a desktop executable.
- Using React Native to deploy the code to IOS and Android devices.

Education

Oregon State University - College of Engineering

December 2015

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science